<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CycloFix</title>
    <link>https://cyclofix.osm.be/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CycloFix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 17:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cyclofix.osm.be/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Other data &amp; tools</title>
      <link>https://cyclofix.osm.be/docs/other-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyclofix.osm.be/docs/other-tools/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to integrate all the information that might be relevant to cyclists into one single map. Here are some other projects and sources you might need.
Cycle projects in Brussels / Belgium Brussels Bike Routeplanner — take the more quite or scenic route through brussels Villo! — public bike renting in Brussels Cycloparking place — secure bicycle parkling in a locked outdoor shed near your house Cycle counter map — how many cyclists are riding there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About OSM</title>
      <link>https://cyclofix.osm.be/docs/about-osm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyclofix.osm.be/docs/about-osm/</guid>
      <description>To maximize the re-usability of the data CycloFix collects, it was decided to use OpenStreetMap (OSM). But why? How does OSM help? You could say OSM is &amp;ldquo;the Wikipedia of maps&amp;rdquo;. Anyone can improve our data. Anyone can re-use it — not necessarily through any official API, but through a whole ecosystem of tools and services that make the data available for a huge range of usecases.
We collected some resources that delve deeper into this topic:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CycloFix: The Story</title>
      <link>https://cyclofix.osm.be/docs/cyclofix-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyclofix.osm.be/docs/cyclofix-story/</guid>
      <description>Let us tell you a little story. Imagine a warm summer day with a gentle breeze. You decide to go for a cycling trip and happen to cross the Brussels Capital Region. Suddenly, however, you hear a silent hiss, you look down and notice a flat tire (starts cursing). Sounds familiar, right?
Except if you happen to have a bicycle pump with you, you are stuck. So what do you do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data validation</title>
      <link>https://cyclofix.osm.be/docs/validating-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyclofix.osm.be/docs/validating-data/</guid>
      <description>When you edit OpenStreetMap (OSM), all your changes are applied automatically. This makes for a fast mapping environment where you can easily work together. But of course, there are risks to this approach. The OpenStreetMap community handles those risks by constant validation.
For this tool, we use the OSMCha. The tool was developped by Mapbox, a company that provides basemaps and other services to large corporations. They provide this tool to any mapper free of charge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapathons and more</title>
      <link>https://cyclofix.osm.be/docs/mapathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyclofix.osm.be/docs/mapathon/</guid>
      <description>A mapathon is a coordinated mapping event where the public is invited to make online map improvements in their local area to improve coverage, basically a kind of crowdsourcing. During #osoc20, we organized a mapathon to boost the CycloFix project. It is important to have the right goals in mind when organizing such an event. Our goal was two-sided: increase the coverage of mapped cycling infrastructure in the Brussels Capital Region (collect as much data as possible) AND build a community to keep the map updated (introducing others to OSM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-using the data and map</title>
      <link>https://cyclofix.osm.be/docs/using-data-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyclofix.osm.be/docs/using-data-map/</guid>
      <description>Re-using and integrating the CycloFix map Share this map Share this map by copying the link below and sending it to friends and family.
https://mapComplete.osm.be/cyclofix.html
When you move the map around, the URL is changed a little bit to reflect where exactly you are looking. So move to the location you want to share, and copy the URL again to share that location: https://mapComplete.osm.be/cyclofix.html?z=16&amp;amp;lat=50.8465573&amp;amp;lon=4.351697
When you change the map background or you hide some of the categories, this is also reflected in the URL, for example: https://mapComplete.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
